<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Pride</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="intro">intro</string>
    <string name="envy">envy</string>
    <string name="vainglory">vainglory</string>
    <string name="sloth">sloth</string>
    <string name="avarice">avarice</string>
    <string name="anger">anger</string>
    <string name="gluttony">gluttony</string>
    <string name="lust">lust</string>
    <string name="pride">PRIDE</string>
    <string name="summary">SUMMARY</string>
    <string name="symptoms">SYMPTOMS</string>
    <string name="reflect">REFLECT</string>
    <string name="notes">Notes</string>
    <string name="puttingToDeath">PUTTING TO DEATH</string>
    <string name="askGod">ASK GOD</string>
    <string name="practice">PRACTICE</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_title">FEELING BITTER WHEN OTHERS HAVE IT BETTER</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_subtitle">RESENTING OTHERS’ GIFTS FROM GOD BECAUSE THEY APPEAR BETTER THAN YOURS</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_summary">"“The bottom line for the envious is how they stack up against others, because they measure their self-worth comparatively. The envious sorrow over another’s good because it excels their own, and because the comparison reveals not only their lack of that particular good, but also their consequent lack of worth. Unlike the possession of goodness (“I am good/this is good), “to excel” is a two-term relation, implying a comparative ranking: “I excel you.”

“Enviers don’t usually envy those who are far removed from their lives and lifestyles, or who are vastly more talented or successful than they are. They tend to envy people to whom they might actually be compared unfavorably, that is, those who are just like them—only better. A writer couldn’t care less if an Olympic athlete wins gold in the 5,000-meter run, while she can barely finish a local 5K road race. But she burns when her colleague gets a rave review on his new novel, while her own published work gets only half-hearted notice…As [Thomas] Aquinas puts it, we envy only those whom we wish to rival or surpass in reputation.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_pride_summary">“The vice of envy is rooted in pride, because the envier takes it to be her prerogative and responsibility to make her own place in the ranking and manufacture her own worth by usurping God’s role: founding their self-worth on their own claims to excellence, creating their own superior status by engineering the downfall of their competitors, and deciding for themselves who is and who is not worthy of the greater gifts.”</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_bible_verse">JAMES 3:13-18</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_reflect">"Envy strikes at the heart of our identity and worth. We envy those who are better than we are in areas that are central to how we define ourselves. 

Spend some time reflecting on what you personally envy others for. What do these things tell you about how you measure your self-worth? 

The danger of envy is that it isn’t just something we feel on the inside. It corrodes our relationships with others by focusing all our time and energy on ourselves. As a result we become more bitter and selfish. It doesn’t just stop there. James tells us that envy leads to disorder and opens us up to every evil practice. 

Consider how envy infects the various aspects of your life."</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_kids">Here’s a simple definition of envy. Envy is unhappiness at the success of others and pleasure at the suffering of others. When we envy, we’re sad when others are glad and glad when they are sad. The values of life are turned upside down.

\n\nThere are many warnings about envy in the Bible, but there is no greater example of its destructive power than the life of <b>King Saul</b>. He is Exhibit A of what happens when envy takes over. The heart of the story is found in <b>I SAMUEL 18:5-12</b>.

\n\nThe story of Saul’s repeated attempts to kill David is meant to warn of the deadly destructive power of envy. What happened to Saul can easily happen to any of us (maybe not murder but jealousy that damages relationships).

\n\nIt’s crucial to identify the real problem of envy. When we envy, our struggle is not with the person we envy. Our real struggle is with God. When we envy, we’re saying, “Lord, you made a mistake when you gave that person so many blessings. I deserve some of what you gave him.” More than that, we’re really accusing God of unfairness. When you envy, you are accusing God of falling down on the job.

\n\nHow can we be set free? Start with being grateful.

\n\n<b>“AND WHATEVER YOU DO, WHETHER IN WORD OR DEED, DO IT ALL IN THE NAME OF THE LORD JESUS, GIVING THANKS TO GOD THE FATHER THROUGH HIM.” COLOSSIANS 3:17</b>

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, teach your kids to be content with what they have at any given time. Resist comparing what your family has to what others have – from a larger house or a newer car, to better grades or more talents. Don’t complain about your circumstances or nurture an attitude of resentment. Help your kids notice all the good that God is doing in your lives. Encourage them to thank God regularly for their blessings, and to thank other people who’ve done something valuable for them. Gratefulness will melt away envy.</string>
    <string name="devo_envy_kids_prayer">Prince of Peace, Help me to not be envious towards my family and friends but to be happy for them and encourage them to do their best. Cleanse me of anything that breaks Your heart, oh Savior. Help me live a righteous life, that I may experience Your love and show love in return to all I come into contact with. In Jesus’ mighty name, Amen!!!</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_title">IMAGE IS EVERYTHING</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_subtitle">TRYING TO APPEAR BETTER THAN WE ARE TO WIN RECOGNITION AND APPROVAL FROM OTHERS</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_summary">"“Most of us know this vice well, even if we have never heard this name for it before. Vainglory is the excessive and disordered desire for recognition and approval from others.”

“When caught in the vice of vain-glory, we want acclaim too much, so much, in fact, that we will accept it whether it is deserved or not.”

“The vainglorious…do not aspire to something because it is excellent. Rather, they seek whatever will bring in the most public applause, whether deserving or not…The whole point for the vainglorious is that others take notice. When we are plagued by this vice, we need people to nod and smile approvingly when we walk by. Vainglory disposes us to be more concerned with our reputation (what others think about us) than with what we really are. For the vainglorious, image is everything.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_pride_summary">“Both pride and vainglory seek to make us the center of the universe. With vainglory, our best energy goes into enhancing and controlling our image, appearance, and reputation. In the end, however, trying to manage our own reputation and manufacture approval for ourselves yields a life of isolation, falsity and shallowness, and self-preoccupation.”</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_bible_verse">MATTHEW 6:1-8</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_reflect">"Vainglory is about making ourselves look better than we really are. In Chinese culture we call this “saving face.” We are worried more about what others think about us than we are with what we really are.

Take some time to consider how much of your time is and energy is directed towards “keeping up appearances”? Write down some specific instances of how vainglory expresses itself in your life.

Reflect on the ways in which the reputation you have built up is a false representation of who you really are.

Take some time to consider the “why” of all your vainglorious pursuits. What ultimately are the pay-offs? How much do these things really matter? What would it look like for you to take Jesus’ counsel about making a habit of doing good things in “secret”?"</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_kids">Prideful people want more than anything else to be "number one"—they seek greatness and superiority, even in ways that appropriately belong only to God. Pride is the root of so much other evil. It is pride that makes some of us think we are better than everyone else, that rules do not apply to us, or that we simply cannot fail whatever we attempt.

\n\nScripture shows us the results of pride through the example of <b>King Nebuchadnezzar</b> in <b>DANIEL 5:20-21</b>. When Nebuchadnezzar became prideful and thought he was better than everyone else, God humbled him. King Nebuchadnezzar lived like an animal (even eating grass, YUCK!) until he came to his senses and repented of his sin. Only then did God then restore Nebuchadnezzar’s kingdom to him.

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, be careful or you’ll end up nurturing enormous egos in your kids if you indulge their selfish impulses by saying “yes” to whatever they want. Instead, set healthy boundaries and stick to them. Teach your kids the importance of working with others instead of expecting to live life on their terms all the time. Require them to treat other people with respect. Help your kids learn why authority is important, and teach them to submit to it. Teach your children how to confess their sins and repent to God.

\n\nHere is a good practice this week: Pray the <b>Lord’s Prayer</b> together. The Lord’s Prayer <b>(Matthew 6:9-13)</b>, prayed earnestly, keeps our pride in check. We pray together, <b>“OUR FATHER IN HEAVEN, HALLOWED BE YOUR NAME. YOUR KINGDOM COME, YOUR WILL BE DONE, ON EARTH AS IT IS IN HEAVEN.”</b>

\n\nDo you see how this prayer is a cure to pride? We are not praying, “Hallowed be <b>MY</b> name. <b>MY</b> kingdom come, <b>MY</b> will be done.” In following Jesus we follow one who called us to serve, who washed his disciples feet, who laid down his life for us. The more you seek God first, the more you will see yourself through God’s eyes.</string>
    <string name="devo_vainglory_kids_prayer">Dear Jesus, you were compassionate with people who saw themselves too often as “being” wrong and bad, as missing the mark. You were honest with people who proudly saw themselves as “being” right and good, always hitting that mark. Be an accurate mirror to each one of us, Lord, reflecting who we are and where we need your grace and instruction in our lives. Amen.</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_title">LAZY ABOUT LOVE</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_subtitle">BEING UNWILLING TO BE OR DO ALL GOD WANTS FROM US BECAUSE THAT WOULD TAKE EFFORT AND WE WANT THE EASY WAY OUT</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_summary">"“Sloth is opposed to the great Christian virtue of diligence—that powerful sense of responsibility, dedication to hard work, and conscientious completion of one’s duties. And what is hard work and dedication at its best, after all, but an expression of love and devotion? The telltale root of our word diligence is the Latin diligere, which means ‘to love.’ Sloth, on this view, is apathy—comfortable indifference to duty and neglect of other human beings’ needs. If you don’t work hard, you don’t care enough. Sloth becomes a sin not merely because it makes us lazy, but because of the lack of love that lies behind that laziness.”

“It is through daily practices and disciplines, whether we feel like doing them or not, that the decision to love is renewed and refreshed, and the commitment of love is kept alive. The slothful person, in this sense, is one who resists the effort of doing day after day after day whatever it takes to keep the bonds of love strong an living and healthy, whether he or she feels particularly inspired about doing it or not.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_pride_summary">“The slothful person ultimately insists on his own way, his own will, his own self-made pseudo-rest. His lack of commitment speaks of an unwillingness to surrender himself to God. It is this resistance that roots the vice of sloth in pride… The slothful person tries to find happiness while evading the daily demands of self-giving love. He prefers his own diligent efforts to make himself happy with shortcuts and quick fixes.”</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_bible_verse">MATTHEW 22:37-40</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_reflect">"Sloth is a serious vice because the entire commitment of one’s life to God is at stake. It is the stubborn resistance to the demands that relationships of love make on us.

One way we avoid such demands is by distracting ourselves. Take some time to consider how sloth in your life expresses itself in constant diversions. List your diversions down.

Take some time to consider what there is to gain from sloth—of avoiding anything that may require effort and hard work. Has it led to greater joy or despair?"</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_kids">Slothfulness is best understood as resisting our identity in Christ and his presence in our hearts. Sloth has more to do with being lazy about love than lazy about our work. Sloth is laziness that keeps us from doing our duty to God and humanity. Sloth is opposed to the great virtue of diligence—that powerful sense of responsibility, dedication to hard work, and conscientious completion of one’s duties. Hard work and dedication at its best is an expression of love and devotion.

\n\nIn <b>PROVERBS 24:30-34</b> we are introduced to a ‘sluggard’, a very lazy man. Here was a man who had the responsibility of caring for a vineyard but he didn’t take his duties seriously. What happens to his vineyard? It becomes overrun with weeds and thorns, making it impossible for anything to grow. Because he was lazy, the wall that protected the vineyard started to crumble and predators could enter in and take what they wanted without resistance. In the end, because the man was slothful, he found himself in poverty and starving.

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, teach your kids to work hard, pursue wisdom, and invest their lives in what matters most. Help them lay aside immediate gratification for the long-term rewards of diligence. Assign your kids chores and other regular responsibilities. Resist procrastination by encouraging them to do their most difficult tasks first so they can reap the fruit of that discipline later. Take a hard look at their schedules and consider whether they’re busy with activities that are truly important (remember church is an important activity!), or are merely spending lots of time on unimportant leisure activities.

\n\nDon’t back down when your kids try to avoid work they need to do – from doing their homework to cleaning their rooms. Even though it’s often easier to do tasks for your kids yourself rather than to try and convince them to do it and following through to make sure it’s done, resist the urge to do for your kids what they really should be doing for themselves. Teach your kids how to effectively budget the limited amount of time and energy they have every day so they’ll learn how to set the right priorities.</string>
    <string name="devo_sloth_kids_prayer">Dear Jesus, forgive us for those times when we are indifferent about your presence in our lives. Forgive us when we are lazy to do the things we know we must do. Help us not to procrastinate and to put things off. Help us discern where we need to be exerting our energies. As we hear your voice more clearly, give us a determined, engaged will to follow you. Amen.</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_title">I WANT IT ALL</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_subtitle">WANTING TO BE ABLE TO PROVIDE FOR OUR NEEDS BY OURSELVES WITHOUT HAVING TO DEPEND ON GOD.</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_summary">"“Greed is an excessive love of or desire for money or any possession money can buy.”

“[Thomas] Aquinas argues that human beings are tempted to seek material wealth because it gives us the illusion of self-sufficiency—and therefore serves as a powerful incentive to deny our need for God. Who among us would want to give up the power to make ourselves comfortable and secure in the world? The possession of money represents this self-sufficiency and the power to secure it, and is a convenient and much less demanding replacement for God.”

“Greed’s inner clutch on the heart can corrode the virtue of generosity and dampen our enthusiasm and eagerness to give freely. At its worst, however, greed also incites us to the obstinate refusal to meet even the demands of basic justice, as we opt instead to keep more than our share. The greedy are excessive to the point of depriving others of what they deserve or need.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_pride_summary">“Greed, like all the deadly sins, is anchored in pride and nourished by it. Prideful greed is the desire to take over God’s role and make sure we get enough for ourselves—or better yet, to make sure we get what we want. It is the desire to be able to provide fully for ourselves, and therefore not to have to depend on God.”</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_bible_verse">LUKE 12:13-21</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_reflect">"John D. Rockefeller was once asked, “How much money is enough?” He responded, “Just a little more.”

How would you answer the question, “How much is enough?”

Jesus reminds us that “a man’s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” One way to think about our possessions is to see them as things we “use” rather than as stuff to store up. Ask yourself, “Why has God given you what you have? What might God want you to do with the things you own? Are there ways they can be used to benefit others and not just yourself?”

Jesus ends by telling us to be “rich towards God.” How do you understand this challenging phrase? What steps can you take, in your day-to-day life, to increase this kind of inner wealth in your life?"</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_kids">Greed is having to great a desire for money or worldly goods. Greed is a heart problem, but it does not necessarily stay hidden inside. Patterns of getting and giving can reveal our hearts\' deepest priorities and attachments. Love of “stuff” will block our spiritual growth because it keeps us from loving God with all our heart, soul, mind, and strength. Greed results in displacing Jesus who has the right to be King on the throne of our lives. That\'s why greed is called <b>"idolatry"</b> in <b>COLOSSIANS 3:5.</b>

\n\nIn <b>1 KINGS 21:2-3</b> we have a perfect example of what greed can lead to in Ahab, king of Israel. Ahab had just about everything but lacked character, and he was married to a woman who was even worse than he was, Jezebel. He was very wealthy. He had one entire palace inlaid with ivory. And he had another palace in Jezreel. One day as he looked out the window of his Jezreel palace he saw a vineyard that he thought would make a nice vegetable garden for himself. The only problem was it belonged to someone else, a man named Naboth. But Naboth refused to sell because he was obedient to God\'s instructions about the land. When Israel first took possession of the land, every family received their plot of ground. The land could never be permanently sold and was to remain in that family\'s possession forever. But instead of respecting Naboth\'s reasons for not selling, look what Ahab did:

\n\n<b>"AHAB WENT HOME, SULLEN AND ANGRY BECAUSE NABOTH THE JEZREELITE HAD SAID, \'I WILL NOT GIVE YOU THE INHERITANCE OF MY FATHERS.\' HE LAY ON HIS BED SULKING AND REFUSED TO EAT." 1 KINGS 21:4</b>

\n\nAhab acted like a spoiled baby. But he demonstrates something we all do. He focused on what he didn\'t have. Ahab expressed no gratitude for all his wealth, his power, or his palaces. Instead, he lay on his bed sulking and fasting in protest for not getting his way.

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, combat greed by helping your kids develop into generous people. Don’t focus on stuff like so many others in our culture do. Rather than simply buying your kids whatever they want, intentionally limit the amount of stuff they have to instill character in them. When they want something extra (more of a want than a need), try to have them earn the money to buy it themselves so they can connect the dots between value and effort. Model a simple lifestyle for them through your own buying choices. Teach your kids the vital difference between focusing on what they can get in this world (as consumers) and what they can give in this world (as contributors). Let them see you treat people in need with love instead of criticizing them. Encourage your kids to give sacrificially rather than placing arbitrary limits on their giving.</string>
    <string name="devo_avarice_kids_prayer">Dear Lord Jesus, we remember that you selflessly gave your life for our sake. As we remember your generosity, teach us how to live increasingly generous lives. Help us grow into truly cheerful givers. Amen.</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_title">HOLY EMOTION OR HELLISH PASSION?</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_subtitle">PERVERTING THE PASSIONATE PURSUIT OF JUSTICE INTO A QUEST FOR PERSONAL REVENGE</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_summary">"“When it is good, anger is a passion for justice, motivated by love for others… Anger turns vicious, however, when it fights for its own selfish cause, not for justice, and when it fights dirty. That is, anger becomes a vice when there are problems with its target—whatever it is that makes us angry—or with the way we try to hit that target—how we express our anger.”

“[Thomas] Aquinas breaks down wrath’s disordered expression into three main categories. We can get angry too easily (for example, when we are quick-tempered); we can get angrier than we should (for instance, when our anger is disproportionate to the offense); and we can stay angry too long (that is, when anger smolders into resentment and grudge holding).”

“’The underlying message of highly angry people,’ according to the American Psychological Association website, is that ’things oughta go my way!’ Angry people tend to feel that…any blocking or changing of their plans is an unbearable indignity and that they should not have to suffer this way. Maybe other people do, but not them!”"</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_pride_summary">“Once we realize that pride is the root of wrath, when we dig deep to discover the causes of our wrath, we must face our assumptions about who we think we are, how much control over ourselves and our world we desire and assume we have, what makes us feel threatened and what makes us feel secure. Whereas wrath is rooted in pride, the strength of gentleness and the steadfastness of love in the face of adversity are rooted in a deep trust in God to handle things.”</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_bible_verse">MARK 3:1-6</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_reflect">"Although we know that Jesus was angry about sin many times, the only time the word is applied to him is here in this passage.

When we get angry our anger can go wrong in 2 main ways: (1) WHAT we get angry about and (2) HOW we express our anger.

In this passage, Jesus shows us the way of righteous anger. Jot down in your own words what Jesus gets angry about and how he expresses his anger. What motivates Jesus’ anger?

Take some time to consider the last time you got angry. What were you angry about? How did you express your anger? What motivated your anger?

Compare your anger with Jesus’ anger. If possible, consider how your anger demonstrates a lack of trust in God."</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_kids">Anger, when it is a holy emotion, has justice as its object and love as its root. Anger becomes a sin when it takes the form of rebellion, revenge, retaliation, causes harm to self or others, or sets an obstacle in the way of our relationship with God.

\n\nThe stories found in <b>1 SAMUEL 20:30-34 &amp; 2 SAMUEL 9:1-8</b> help us to understand the difference between sinful anger and mercy (loving-kindness and compassion). In the first story, Saul feared David’s military skill and rising status. In a rage, he even tried to kill his son Jonathan for being David’s friend. In the second story, when David became king, he sought out Saul’s descendant, not to take revenge, but to show him compassion.

\n\nAnger in itself isn’t either good or bad; the key is in how you express it. Sinful anger is unworthy irritation and lack of self-control. Scripture teaches us <b>“IN YOUR ANGER DO NOT SIN. DO NOT LET THE SUN GO DOWN WHILE YOU ARE STILL ANGRY, AND DO NOT GIVE THE DEVIL A FOOTHOLD.” EPHESIANS 4:26-27</b>

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, teach your kids that while getting angry at the right things (like injustices) and doing so in healthy ways that don’t harm others is fine, they need to control destructive anger. Do all you can to create an environment of peace and quiet – not tension – at home. Give them the security of knowing that you love them unconditionally and will always be willing to forgive them for their mistakes.

\n\nWhenever your kids do become angry for the right reasons, give them legitimate ways of expressing their frustration or resolving injustices. Provide a safe place for them to process offenses and let off steam in healthy ways. Teach your kids not to retaliate through revenge when someone hurts or wrongs them. Show them how to rely on God’s power to help them forgive. Help your kids continue to keep in mind that they’re accountable to God and others for what they say and do – both good and bad.</string>
    <string name="devo_anger_kids_prayer">Dear Jesus, when you lived here, you showed anger—and got it right. Evil made you angry, like innocent people getting hurt or pious people who misrepresented God. We show anger, too—but we often get it wrong. Things that hurt our egos, others who get something we want, or small hassles that upset our plans make us angry. Help us be angry about the things that make you angry. But help us, also, to live with your patience and mercy. Amen.</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_title">FEEDING YOUR FACE AND STARVING YOUR HEART</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_subtitle">TRYING TO USE THE PLEASURE OF EATING TO ATTAIN SPIRITUAL FULLNESS AND SATISFACTION</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_summary">"“Gluttony is really not about how much we’re eating, but about how our eating reflects how much pleasure we take in eating food and why. Eating is meant to be pleasurable, and so is feeling filled after being hungry. These pleasures…are all good God-given gifts…The main question we should be asking is not, ‘How much is too much?’ but rather, ‘How dominated by the desire for this pleasure am I? How difficult would it be to have to give it up or do without it?’ The trouble with gluttony is that it reduces eating to an exercise in gratifying my own desires for physical pleasures, consuming whatever I think will make me full and satisfied.”

“Gluttony’s excessive pursuit of the pleasures of the table eventually dulls our appreciation for the food we eat, the pleasure we take in eating it, those with whom we eat, and the God who created what we eat and gave us the ability to take pleasure in it.”

“What really matters is that whatever and when-ever we eat, we not be so overly attached to the pleasure that we cannot easily and uncomplainingly choose to give it up when duty or necessity requires this.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_pride_summary">“When the gluttonous feel need or emptiness, they do not want to have to depend on God or wait on God to fill it. The pleasure of food is not only readily available, but some-thing we can use to quell our own feelings of need and longing. With food, we can comfort ourselves, fill ourselves, provide pleasure for ourselves—if only physically, and if only for a short while. The glutton’s pursuit of happiness is found in what he can do, not in what God will give him. The addictive quality of pleasure seeking is seated, often enough, in this need for control over our own ability to be happy and full. This is pride.”</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_bible_verse">MATTHEW 4:1-11</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_reflect">"The first temptation Jesus faces in the desert is to turn stone into bread. Jesus famously answers by quoting Deut. 8:3, “Man does not live on bread alone, but on every word that comes from the mouth of God.”

On a scale of 1-10 (1 being really easy and 10 being really hard), rate how difficult it would be to go a whole day without any food.

How about going a whole day without reading Scripture?

Take some time to reflect on whether you have been living on bread alone?

Consider how you might be starving your heart while feeding your face."</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_kids">Gluttony has been both oversimplified and misunderstood. As a vice, gluttony is something habitual. It is a routine or a pattern that gets woven into our character. As a vice it is a sinful habit. Gluttony is often associated with food, but basically it is a pursuit of pleasure. While you may not find yourself craving food compulsively, gluttony may still be a concern. Whereas lust is concerned more with intimacy and the satisfaction that comes with feeling connected with another person, gluttony pursues physical pleasure for its own sake. Gluttony involves an addiction to a physical pleasure (like playing video games, watching TV, or eating bowl after bowl of ice cream).

\n\nGluttony is not just about weight or body shape. It’s about trying to satisfy our appetite for anything (food, power, fun, even beauty or thinness!) in ways that put that desire at the center of life. In gluttony, we end up serving a false god.

\n\nIn <b>MATTHEW 6:25-34</b>, Jesus invites us to trust that God really cares for us. In God’s hands, he said, we are safe for all eternity, no matter what challenges this life brings. Jesus saw, as we often do not, that our preoccupation with food and clothing is usually rooted in fear. We consume more and more (and more) now, because we fear that sometime we may not have enough.

\n\nIn <b>TITUS 2:11-14</b>, the Apostle Paul says the point of self-control is not to take good things out of life, but to free us to live effectively and joyfully for God. Self-control serves the same purpose as the brakes or steering on a car. They aren’t to eliminate the car’s power and speed. Instead, they direct the car, making the power and speed useful and effective.

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, if you allow your kids to feed an uncontrollable appetite, that appetite – instead of their faith – will end up controlling their lives. Help your kids accept and celebrate their bodies the way God made them. Teach your kids how to make decisions with self-discipline rather than just indulging in whatever looks and feels good at the time. Instead of just giving your kids whatever they want, keep helping them make healthy choices.</string>
    <string name="devo_gluttony_kids_prayer">Dear God, bless us with a good appetite for You. Instead of our own wants, wishes and appetites, Lord, we desire to be consumed by our love for You. Thank you for promising to set us free from anything that is not You and is not from You. Empower us to control and direct our energies wisely in our lives. Help us always to seek first Your kingdom and Your righteousness. Amen.</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_title">CRIMES OF PASSION</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_subtitle">SEEKING SEXUAL PLEASURE AND GRATIFICATION FOR MYSELF AT THE COST OF FULLY HUMAN RELATIONSHIPS WITH OTHERS</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_summary">"“In a nutshell, lust is the excessive desire for my own sexual pleasure.”

“The problem is lust’s reductive impulses: to reduce sexual pleasure to one’s own individual gratification, apart from a relationship to a person; or to reduce it to the only end we have in view, apart from all its other purposes; or to strip it down to its purely physical dimension, apart from its integration into our full humanity.”

“In lust, sexual pleasure is divorced from love and mutual self-giving. And when we lust we certainly want nothing to do with giving life and the future commitments that it might bring—if we even register the thought that the organs involved are reproductive by design.”

“Lust is a vice…because it does not honor the fullness of sex, and it alienates people from each other just when they are sup-posed to be experiencing intimate union. There’s a betrayal of meaning in lust’s use of sex for nothing but self-gratification, and it is difficult to be lustful without feeling that loss at some level. If one is successful in becoming immune to the goods involved in sex, one has also been successful in becoming less fully human.”"</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_pride_summary">“Lust is the habit of trying to engineer my own happiness for myself, on my own terms. In lust, my own pleasure is the goal, and I decide where to get it, and when, and with whom. My life revolves around my desires, wants, and ‘needs.’ I disown my need for God’s love or the love of others… Unlike one who risks depending on the love of another and who risks giving himself to another, the lustful one chooses to be autonomous, providing his good for himself… Both our independence and our need to define and create a false happiness for ourselves are telltale hallmarks of pride.”</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_bible_verse">MATTHEW 5:27-30</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_reflect">"Sexual desires are a natural and beautiful thing—part of the wonder of being human. They are also powerful and we often underestimate their force and hold on us. Maybe that’s why Jesus uses such graphic imagery in describing the lengths we should take to control them—gouge your eye out, cut off your hand. Jesus isn’t asking us to literally maim our bodies. He is trying to say in the strongest possible way that we need to take lust seriously.

Take some time to consider what having a lustful habit says about the kind of person you are becoming. How does it deform your capacity to love? How do your habits of pleasure-seeking corrupt your relationship with God?

Often times, in our weakest moments, we tend to rationalize what we want even when we know it’s wrong. What types of excuses do you use with lust? Take some time to consider how these might be signs of pride in you that reject God’s good design for you."</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_kids">Lust is a strong, super-duper craving for something or someone and usually begins as a sin of weakness; people get carried away by curiosity or strong desires and often get caught up in the moment and underestimate the force that holds them powerless. Lust can be described as a strong passion for power, or knowledge. We can even lust after another person; being attracted to somebody but not in a romantic or personal way. When we lust after someone, we ignore their needs to fulfill our own needs. So lust can be very selfish.

\n\nAs Christians, we seek to honor God who wants every part of us, who is concerned for our thoughts and feelings, and the sins of the heart and mind that bear fruit in our actions.

\n\n<b>“DO YOU NOT KNOW THAT YOUR BODY IS THE TEMPLE OF THE HOLY SPIRIT, WHO IS IN YOU, WHOM YOU HAVE RECEIVED FROM GOD? YOU ARE NOT YOUR OWN; YOU WERE BOUGHT AT A PRICE. THEREFORE HONOR GOD WITH YOUR BODY.” 1 CORINTHIANS 6:19-20</b>

\n\n<b>Parents</b>, trust that God will give your kids the power to resist temptation – especially if you regularly pray for them and talk with them openly and honestly about the challenges they face in any area. We want to help craft and maintain a lifestyle for our children leading them naturally into good choices that produce good consequences. More important than good behaviors, we hope to inspire our children to return God\'s love with a lifestyle that loves and honors Him.

\n\n<b>For parents of older children</b>:  Be sure to have plenty of planned and purposeful discussions about what your kids are facing (media pressure, peer pressure, etc.) instead of just reacting to surprise questions they ask or unexpected situations in which they find themselves. Do all you can to protect your kids from dangers, such as by installing Web-filtering software to prevent pornography on your home computer, encouraging modesty, and teaching your teens how to properly respect themselves and others.</string>
    <string name="devo_lust_kids_prayer">Lord, thank you for all you are and for all you do. We know that, with you by our side, as a family, we can overcome any temptation. Thank you for pouring your Spirit on us. We  praise you and lift up your name. Thank you, Lord. In your Holy Name we pray. Amen.</string>
    <string name="for_the_kids">FOR THE KIDS</string>
    <string name="preface">PREFACE</string>
    <string name="preface_body">During the forty day season of Lent, we remember that Jesus spent forty days preparing for his ministry by fasting and acknowledging those temptations that might distract him from obedience to God (Matthew 4:1-11). We hope that this devotional will help us to do the same, reflecting on our sin and on the things we have allowed to get in the way of following God.</string>
    <string name="preface_part1">PART I: WHAT IS LENT?</string>
    <string name="preface_part2">PART II: WHAT ARE THE SEVEN DEADLY SINS?</string>
    <string name="guidelines">GUIDELINES</string>
    <string name="timeline">SUGGESTED TIMELINE</string>
    <string name="credits">CREDITS</string>
    <string name="credit_caption">All the material on the seven deadly sins in this devotional is based on the book \"Glittering Vices\" by Rebecca Konyndyk DeYoung (Professor of Philosophy at Calvin College). If you found going through these pages helpful, we would encourage you to pick up a copy of this book to read for yourself!</string>
    <string name="prayer">A PRAYER</string>

</resources>